[music]
>> Welcome to the second part of our
in-studio interview with John Kiryakou,
who I've had the pleasure of hosting
here in Nicosia for the last 3 days.
Right off the first part of our
interview, we transition now to
something different. It's the let's get
to know John apart of the interview.
So, John has become one of the most
recognizable faces in the world, and
I've even witnessed it here in Cyprus in
the smallest of tavernas or souvlaki
places I've taken him to. People just
come up to the table like, "Aren't you?"
Anyway, so this is amazing. It's crazy.
He And we all know how he's become
famous.
But appearing on the biggest podcasters
in the world the last year certainly has
helped to that. So, while millions feel
they already know him as that older
gentleman told you today when we were
having lunch,
he said, "We feel like we know you,
right?"
>> Yeah.
Uh
like he's someone they can sit down, you
know, and have a conversation with.
Tonight, I'm I'm going to go a a step
further. I want to bring out a side of
John that we don't usually get to see
because even with someone as open as
John is, there's always
more beneath the surface. So, John,
welcome back again. Kalos Oris es.
>> Thank you so much. To our studio here in
Nicosia. Very, very glad to be here.
>> Yeah, it's it's it's been amazing the
last few days spending time with you.
You've met the family. We've also, you
know, gone around and um
had meetings with important people, but
you've also, you know, been exposed to
the history of Cyprus and not just I'm
not just talking about 1974, the
medieval history, the religious history,
but we'll get to that later. So, John,
12 months ago
when you were just starting to, you
know,
break through the global
stage
and appear on these major podcasters,
did you have any sense that things would
accelerate this fast? No. No sense of it
at all. You know, it's funny until very
recently, just the last 8 weeks, I had a
personal policy of saying yes to just
about every podcast request. Mhm.
>> Right? I enjoy the give and take. I
enjoy the banter. I enjoy talking about
current events and politics. And I I
gave interviews to, you know,
15-year-old high school kids. Good for
you. I I said yes to everybody.
Um and I did it only because it was fun
for me.
I wasn't thinking about an algorithm.
I just wasn't. It never occurred to me
that this had something to do with an
algorithm and it was going to take off.
And then it took off.
It started with it started a year ago
last October with the Danny Jones
podcast in Tampa,
the Dalton Fisher podcast in New Jersey,
and the Julian Dorey podcast. They're
all friends.
So, I did those three podcasts. And And
we are friends, I should add. And uh
and it triggered something in the
algorithm.
So, it elevated me to a to a higher
level, which was great because I was
starting my own podcast. And I wanted to
I wanted to try to accumulate as many
subscribers and followers as I could.
>> Yeah.
That led to a speaking tour of the UK
and Ireland. And it led to interviews
with outlets that I would never have had
um access to. Tucker Carlson. Tucker and
I were old friends, but but he had left
Fox News and started his own podcast,
and I wasn't big enough to go on that
podcast until I was. Mhm. So, Tucker
Carlson, and then that led to Patrick
Bet David, and then that led to Joe
Rogan, and then that one led to Diary of
a CEO.
>> Mhm.
So, 8 weeks ago,
I was in Dubai,
and my niece
uh called me and said, "Theo John,
you're exploding on Tik Tok." And I
said, "Why?"
And she said, "I don't know, but it's
like gone crazy."
Well, it turned out that there was a
20-year-old sophomore
at the University of Texas who took my
Diary of a CEO podcast and cut it into
shorts, but he gave me an Alvin and the
Chipmunks high-pitched voice and laser
beams shooting out of my eyes and it
just
hit with Gen Z.
That's all fun and games, but the
important thing is I'm a 61-year-old man
with access to Gen Z. Mhm. And yes,
they're all having fun with it, but
they're
discussing and considering very
important ideas. Correct. And so, it's
taken on a life of its own. I All of a
sudden, I'm represented by the largest
uh talent agency in the world and I'm
I'm meeting with
Hollywood titans Mhm. about some of
these these issues and about making
movies and
and TV series and I I've written nine
books. They want my 10th one to be
a novel, fiction, which I've never
written fiction before, but I'm already
now 10,000 words into it. Life has
changed completely in the last eight
weeks only because this kid
put me on Tik Tok. Bless him. Mhm.
>> Looks as if it does. Mhm. Yeah. So,
you've become officially the cool uncle
in the family.
>> Right? Yeah, that's great, right?
>> I've had three marriage proposals. Oh,
really?
>> Yeah. I get weird stalker people that,
you know, I've had to call the FBI and
then the FBI got involved and
Well, it comes with the territory.
>> Yeah.
So, two decades since leaving the CIA.
>> Yes.
>> It's a bit more. You left in 2004.
>> years now. Right. Is it hard to switch
off the mindset of, you know, the
the instinct of not to trust easily, the
urge to read people immediately, and to
always stay on, you know, even on days
when you don't feel like it? Yeah, it's
it's not possible to turn it off.
>> You are so highly trained. It is so It
is so drilled into you. It becomes
second nature.
I've been out for 22 years. I still
constantly scan my rearview inside view
mirrors for surveillance. Wow.
Constantly.
Constantly trying to size people up.
You know, what are their real
intentions? What do they want from me?
The CIA taught us to trust no one.
I learned that the hard way. Oh, yes. Um
but yeah, I trust no one.
Let me ask you something that I'm sure a
lot of people are curious about, and if
not, I'm curious about.
Um does the CIA have James Bond-type
gadgets, you know,
um like the pen that you'd flick and it
would detonate a bomb, or the
Google-type glasses long before they
even were made available to the public?
Yes. Okay. 20 years ago, I would have
said no.
Because it was far easier and far
cheaper just to buy whatever gadget you
needed to do an operation. Okay. When I
was in in Pakistan
uh in 2002,
we had to fly a technical team out to
create a device that we needed uh to
track him.
That was unusual.
Uh normally, we would just buy software
or buy a gadget. But then, in the
immediate aftermath of 9/11,
the Congress gave the CIA a waiver
allowing it to invest in technology
companies. Like to invest to buy shares.
Mm. Which doesn't make any sense, cuz
how is government by how this one agency
has billions of dollars to invest in
tech, but that's what they started
doing. And they invested they were the
first investor in the company Palantir,
which is now a multi-billion dollar
intelligence Silicon Valley intelligence
concern.
And it's not just Palantir, it's a whole
bunch of different technology companies.
And so
because they're such significant
investors, they have access to the
technology as it's being developed and
they can help to customize it to their
own intelligence needs.
So 20 years ago, 25 years ago, no, those
gadgets didn't exist. They were just in
the James Bond movies. Today, yes, of
course they exist. Palantir founded by a
fellow Stanford alum, Peter Thiel.
>> That's exactly right. So you never ended
up using any one of those gadgets.
>> No. Okay. Never. Okay.
>> There used to be a shop in London with a
sister shop in New York called the spy
shop.
And every time I'd pass through London,
I would go to the spy shop and buy a
little, you know, pinhole camera or, you
know, something. Just for fun.
We bought a lot of the equipment that we
needed at the spy shop.
>> Really? That's crazy.
>> Yeah.
Why reinvent the wheel? Why spend a
million dollars developing a tool when
you can go to the spy shop and buy it
for a thousand dollars?
>> is still around, right? You know, I I
look I I haven't been able to find them.
I think they've sort of been overtaken
by the technology. The technology
advances so quickly that they can't
really keep up. I had a friend too from
Washington
who was a
he was an attorney and he quit his job
as an attorney to move to Southern
California and open up his own spy
gadget
store and development shop and that
lasted about five years and then went it
went out because the technology was just
changing too quickly. So as soon as you
order something and you put it on on
it's already outdated and there's
something better that's coming.
Now, you publicly wrote to Edward
Snowden, right? Was it in 2013? 2013,
summer. So, if Edward Snowden is
watching this interview, what would you
want to say to him today? It's been many
years since then. I would say not to
lose faith. Ed Snowden went public with
his revelations of mass
dragnet surveillance against American
citizens in the summer of 2013
um at great, great personal risk. Uh he
he was trying to make his way to
Ecuador.
And when he was in the transit lounge at
Moscow Airport, John Kerry, who was
Secretary of State at the time, uh
canceled his passport and stranded him
in Russia. This is one thing I really
hate, Suzie, is when people say he
defected to Russia. No, he didn't. He
was in the transit lounge and John Kerry
stranded him I didn't know in Russia.
Everybody's forgotten that. Yeah. So, he
never made his way to Ecuador and it's a
good thing he didn't Oh, yeah. because
the Ecuadorian government flipped, it
became pro-American, they gave up Julian
Assange, Exactly. and they would have
given up Ed Snowden and he would be in
prison for the rest of his life. So,
what I would say to him is keep the
faith because he was right
in what he did. He was right to report
that the American government was spying
on its own people illegally and even
though
we still have
Section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence
Surveillance Act,
every 2 years when it comes up, fewer
and fewer and fewer members vote in
favor of it.
And so, eventually he's going to be
vindicated.
>> Oh, wow. Mhm. Wow. So,
don't lose hope
>> Don't lose hope. Okay.
He can get in touch with you if he wants
to? Oh, yeah, I've been in touch with
him a couple of times. Yeah.
Now, when you were released from prison,
I think you had mentioned that you would
have you would like to have to get
involved in prison reform. Is prison
reform something still that you'd like
to be involved in today or you don't
have the time? Funny that you ask.
>> Why?
Suzy.
A week ago
on Saturday
it was early in the morning, 8:00 8:30,
I'm driving down the street in
Washington and my phone rings.
And I look at it and it's a number
that's not in my phone. It says Chicago
mobile.
Normally I don't answer question
phone calls rather that
I don't know the caller. I thought maybe
it's somebody important they're calling
me this early on a Saturday morning. I
answer.
It's the director of the Bureau of
Prisons.
I was shocked. He introduced himself and
I said, "To what do I owe the pleasure
of a call from the director of the
Bureau of Prisons?" And he said Yeah.
"You've been talking about the
Bureau of Prisons for the last 10
years."
And I said
"On the contrary I've been talking
about the Bureau of Prisons for the last
13 years."
And he says, "Thus the reason for my
call.
You don't just talk about the
Bureau of Prisons. You offer solutions."
He's right, you know.
>> Uh-huh? I I do. I've written about this
extensively hundreds of times.
And so he said
"The president has tasked me with
tearing the Bureau of Prisons down and
rebuilding it." And I said, "The Bureau
of Prisons is a failure because it's
corrupt and everybody in it is corrupt.
We should be ashamed globally ashamed
of the of the conditions inside American
prisons. They're third world."
And said, "And that's why I'm calling.
Would you be willing to serve on an
advisory board for me?" Okay. He said,
"I need advice on how to do this." And I
said, "I'm all in."
And so, I've joined this advisory board.
He asked me if there was anybody I could
recommend to also join this advisory
board, and I said, "Yes.
There are two people that I I highly
recommend." And I made a reference.
I I connected them. Is this the first
time you're saying this to
>> First time I've telling anybody I'm
telling anybody.
>> then. This is This is a big deal. And it
gives hope to a lot of people and a lot
of people's families. I can't tell you
how many times
I would go to the prison prison
commissary
and I would need, let's say, I needed to
buy deodorant Yeah. or Pop-Tarts or a
battery for my radio.
And there are none. Why? Because the
guards backed their pickup truck up to
the loading dock and stole all of it.
And then they sold them on black Yeah,
exactly. They sold it on eBay or on the
black market.
We're talking about tens of thousands
just in our little prison. Tens of
thousands of dollars
stolen. And nobody batted an eye because
they were all stealing. I'll give you
another example.
Um there is a 30% markup on everything
in every prison commissary. And that 30%
is supposed to go to buy gym equipment,
workout equipment TVs, whatever.
Yeah. It went to buy gym equipment and
workout equipment and TVs for the
guards' lounge.
We didn't get any of it. It's our own
money.
And they just stole it from us.
Uh the guards are supposed to eat
whatever is being prepared in the
cafeteria. Well, what's being prepared
in the cafeteria is animal-grade food.
It says it on the box, "Not for human
consumption. Feed use only."
Um
there was a prisoner who came up to me
one time with a with a tub of Sabra
hummus.
I said, "Where in the world did you find
hummus?"
And he said, uh "I stole it from the
guards' lounge.
They're using our money to buy hummus."
So, I had him steal some for me. I had
to pay him handsomely for it.
But, uh
they weren't eating the garbage, the
animal-grade food that uh we were
eating. How about the fish? I remember
now you said you told me about the fish
that they Fish my very first day in
prison. So, what what do you call it?
Yes, we called it sewer trout. Sewer
trout. On my very first full day in
prison, I reported to prison on a
Thursday. On Friday,
it's fish day.
And I said, "Oh, good. I like fish." And
one of the Italians told me, "Oh, you're
not going to like this fish. Don't eat
it. We call it sewer trout."
So, I went down to the cafeteria and I
see these boxes stacked behind the food
line.
And it says, "Alaskan cod."
Okay.
"Product of China." So, it's not
Alaskan.
And then underneath it says,
"Feed use only.
Not for human consumption." It's written
on the box. It is not to be fed to
humans.
I'll tell you something worse, Susie.
We got a memo
from the warden one time, right?
Everybody gets a memo.
All hands memo, it's called. And it's an
apology from the warden. We would have
taco night
every Wednesday night. It was the worst
ground beef I've ever experienced in my
life.
To the point where I've never eaten a
taco again.
Since?
>> Uh-huh. Wow. I haven't eaten a taco in
what, 13 years? I just I can't.
>> so tasty, though.
>> I can't do it. So, taco night,
we were accidentally fed dog food
instead of ground beef.
Right? It He said, "It's not our fault.
Uh it was a mix-up at the um at the meat
factory."
Whatever they call it.
And the
the owner of the meat factory is going
to pay a fine and the fine goes to the
Bureau of Prisons. It doesn't go to us.
But I'll tell you, the shame was not
that they fed us dog food.
The shame was they fed us dog food and
we couldn't even tell the difference.
So,
I mean,
Mhm. who knows other times? Exactly. Oh
god. I was lucky in that I I was a very
high-profile prisoner. And so strangers
were just sending money into my
commissary account. And so I was able to
buy real food. I could buy bags of
chicken or bags of tuna. I could buy
tortillas to make whatever. I could buy
rice.
Um
and so after my first year
[clears throat] or 9 months, I didn't
eat their food.
It was too unhealthy. It was too
dangerous.
So, there's a lot of work to do and
hopefully
uh whatever the commission comes out
with the report, it's going to be
implemented. Yeah, I hope so. Yeah.
Although, again,
Donald Trump is only president for 2 and
1/2 more years. Is that really enough
time to reform an entire,
you know, major global prison system?
No.
Now, let's let's turn to something
lighter. Let's go back to
uh that. Do you or did you ever have
anything remotely resembling what we see
movies uh that involve spies uh like Mr.
& Mrs. Smith, you know, a hidden room
containing a stash, a secret stash of
weapons or anything like that? No? No,
nobody does. But there are movies that
are very, very true to life. Like Argo
was completely true. Really? Completely,
totally true.
>> Yeah.
Uh those guys were heroes at the agency.
Um The Recruit was Yeah. almost
completely true. The only difference is
they didn't beat us in training.
Training was hard, but they didn't beat
us like they beat him.
Uh Bridge of Spies?
Oh, I love that.
>> 100% historically accurate.
>> a Yeah, a true story.
>> Yeah, so there are there are a lot of
movies that are that are right on, but
the action ones, it's totally made up.
>> hidden agents don't have hidden rooms
with stash. Okay.
>> No, no. But, have you ever, as John,
acted like Robert De Niro did in the
Meet the Parents movie, you know,
holding holding someone's wrist to read
or intimidate them socially? Did you
ever do that?
You there?
>> Once. Really?
I did it once, and the guy started
crying.
>> Yeah. Why did you do it? You wanted to
intimidate him?
>> I wanted to intimidate him. But, it was
a on a for on a social level, or was it
for work? He thought it was a social
meeting. Oh.
>> For me, it was a it was a work meeting.
Can you say more about it?
>> He claimed access to a to a target that
we were very, very interested in.
And so, he came to the embassy and just
volunteered. Greek embassy? American
embassy.
Yeah, the American embassy.
>> Where? What What
>> No, I can't tell you where. Okay, sorry.
I'm just asking you the questions, and
if you can't, just tell me I can't.
>> Yeah, I can't tell you. So, he comes to
the embassy. I have information on this
guy who is a known target of ours. I
said, "Okay, give me the information."
Well, he said, "I'm going to need
something from you. I want money. I want
this. I want that. I want to resettle in
the United States." I said, "Yeah, if
you have access to this guy, I'll give
you all that stuff."
So,
he I said, "Give Give me Give me your
driver's license, your passport,
whatever, so I could see, you know, who
I'm dealing with. I'm going to send it
back to headquarters for a name trace."
And I said, "Come back in 24 hours."
So,
he didn't realize that we put a
surveillance on him to follow him for
the rest of the day. And he was just a
dishwasher at a restaurant.
He didn't have access to this target. He
was just washing dishes.
But he thought he could lie his way into
the United States and I'm going to make
him rich and you know, might as well
give it a try, right? Yeah. But he was
an [clears throat] idiot.
And so he came back the next day, he's
wearing a suit the next day.
And so I did the Robert De Niro thing on
him and I wouldn't let go of his wrist.
He got very nervous.
And then I threatened him.
And he started crying and I said, don't
you ever come back here or to any other
American embassy anywhere in the world.
And then one of my colleagues walked up
to him and just went click and took his
picture. He was bawling.
And then left as quickly as he could.
That's a fun story.
I said afterwards, I can't believe I had
to waste two hours on that guy.
Wait.
That took two hours? The whole um Well,
an hour the one day and an hour the next
day.
>> Okay.
Yeah. Fun.
So, rapid fire now. Okay.
Quick round.
One word or one short phrase. Ready?
It's a few, but I want to ask them.
Bernie Sanders.
Love him.
Rand Paul.
Like him.
>> [laughter]
>> Why not love him? I love him.
>> [snorts]
>> Rapid fire.
>> Okay.
Marjorie Taylor Greene.
I've come to respect her.
Matt Gaetz.
Did I pronounce it correctly? Funny that
I've come to respect him.
Pete Hegseth.
War criminal.
Marco Rubio.
Another war criminal.
Kamala Harris.
Loser with a capital L on her head.
John Kerry.
The stupidest smart guy I've ever
encountered.
And certainly the most arrogant.
Nancy Pelosi.
Stayed around way, way too long. Chuck
Schumer.
Corrupt.
And still around. And still around.
Bill Clinton.
Far more popular as a president. He had
a true aura about him.
Hillary.
Demonic.
Bush senior.
>> [sighs]
>> Complicated, yet very, very popular at
the CIA.
Bush junior.
Um
not bright at all
and one of the weakest presidents
in my lifetime. Barack Obama.
Criminal.
Trump.
No comment.
JFK.
One of the greatest presidents in
American history. If he had been able to
to actually survive
um
the entire face of the world would be
different today. Agreed.
Dr. Gerald Post. Oh, one of my personal
heroes.
Recruited me into the CIA and wanted
only the best for me.
Andres Bustamante.
Not important enough to even bother
commenting on.
Former CIA director Gina Haspel. Bloody
Gina Haspel, a war criminal.
Former CIA director John Brennan. The
worst of all of the criminals.
He deserves to be in prison for a very
long time. And if all goes well, that's
exactly where he'll end his life.
Abu Zubaydah.
Poor Abu Zubaydah. Abu Zubaydah Yes.
Abu Zubaydah should be should be free
and living with his family today. He's
still in Guantanamo. Still in
Guantanamo. Is he in isolation?
Uh I mean they're all in
relative isolation. They're in cages.
Let's go back to the list. Bibi
Netanyahu? Uh probably the foremost war
criminal on the planet. Putin?
A strong leader. Uh
I don't agree with everything he does
certainly and certainly he has blood on
his hands. People don't just fall off
hotel balconies for no reason.
But a strong leader with a well a
long-term view.
Xi Jinping?
Oh, a strong leader with an even longer
long-term view.
IRGC?
I am of the belief that the IRGC is a
terrorist organization. Okay.
The most moral army in the world as they
themselves purport to be, the IDF?
One of the worst criminal organizations
at work in the world today.
Joe Rogan?
I like Joe Rogan.
Joe Rogan gave me a big boost being on
his show. I I hope to do it again.
Patrick Bet-David?
You can plead the fifth if you want.
Yeah, I think I'll generally plead I
like Patrick. He's a nice guy, but I
think otherwise I'm going to plead the
fifth.
>> Okay. Tucker Carlson?
>> I love Tucker Carlson. He's been a good
friend to me.
And uh
I think he would be a brilliant
president of the United States.
King Leonidas of Sparta?
>> [laughter]
>> One of the greatest figures in history.
>> Right. Somebody of whom we should all be
proud.
Mhm. Especially us the Greeks.
>> Especially.
Another great Greek. Well, I shouldn't
be commenting. Alexander the Great?
>> Yeah, the greatest the greatest of of
all Greeks who ever lived.
>> You're going to have problem with your
girlfriend.
1821, those who know know. Greek War of
Independence.
>> Yeah.
One of the
most important events in global history.
It you know, just reading about the
heroes of the revolution, it makes me so
proud to be Greek.
And when you look at how they
Oh, this is rapid fire. But anyway,
yeah, it's this is something that should
be studied in schools all around the
world.
Vinyl records.
Did you say that one again?
>> Vinyl records.
>> records. I I buy them all the time. And
I'm very happy that my kids
my kids have discovered vinyl. And they
in fact
my youngest one time was singing along
in the car with a a classic rock song
from the early 70s. And I said I said,
"Charlie." His name is Kiriakos. I said,
"Charlie, how do you know this song?"
And he said, "Are you kidding me? You
play it all the time."
>> [laughter]
>> Astrophotography.
Oh, I'm actually Well, of course, you
probably saw that.
I I work
constantly. I have no hobbies. And I
decided for my own health, I needed to
develop a hobby. And so I took up
astrophotography. And I'm kind of good
at it. Mhm. I've seen the photos.
>> [laughter]
>> Book a book or a books you're reading
right now?
Yeah, [snorts] well
>> to start reading?
>> Your husband just gave me a wonderful
book written Well, it's not written by,
but it's the words of Vaios Baiseos. And
uh I'm going to start it today. Yeah, he
just gave it to you. He just got back
from Mount Sinai, Ayon Oros. He gifted
it to you too.
>> Yes. I can't wait to get into it.
Last few ones. Potatoes.
I'm a long time fan of potatoes, but I
can't eat them anymore.
>> I'm throwing it out especially
considering the story behind the name
Kiriago being linked to a stolen potato.
>> [laughter]
>> Right, my great my great great
grandfather was arrested in Rhodes for
stealing a potato. He was starving. And
he stole a potato and he was arrested.
Our family name was was Christodoulou.
And when he went to court, they asked
him, "Didn't Antonomasas?" He said,
"Marcos Marcos D Marcos D Kiriakou."
And they wrote Marcos Kiriakou and he
never fixed it. That means Marcos the
son of Kiriakou.
>> The son of Kiriakou's, right? And so we
have one branch of the family that's
Christodoulou
and one branch of the family that's
Kiriakou.
And it just was never corrected.
Christos and Stella, your parents?
>> My parents, wonderful wonderful parents.
I was blessed to have You know, it's
funny. I thought that everybody had
great parents like that when I was
growing up and it just wasn't the case.
Greece?
My my homeland.
When I got in trouble, the Greek
ambassador called me and said, "How can
we be helpful?" And I said, "You can
give me citizenship." Oh. And they did.
That's how. And all five of my children.
Oh, wow.
>> Mhm. I'm proud to be a Greek citizen.
Very proud. But how about Cyprus? You
just did the DNA test. You need to tell
the viewers. We're very proud.
>> Yeah, I'm very proud of this. I was
asked to speak at the uh
the uh Cypriots of the diaspora uh
conference in Limassol and around the
same time that the invitation came, I
did a DNA test. And it turned out I'm
24% Cyprus and a Cypriot and I told my
cousin Mark Kiriakou. I said uh
I said, "Papou always said that we were
from Crete originally." And he said,
"Not Crete, Cyprus." I said, "No, he
didn't say Cyprus. He said Crete."
Well, it was Cyprus.
And I I
I'm sure that you are from Cyprus
originally because the surname Kiriakou
you don't find it often in Greece. It's
a very common surname in Cyprus.
>> It's true. But you have to say that the
24% Cypriot is the most percentage of of
any country
>> of any Yeah, because otherwise it's
divided between
Greek Islands and the Black Sea and
>> got more Cyprus in you than Greece.
>> Yeah. So you're a Cypriot.
>> I'm a Cypriot. Yep. Greek Orthodoxy. Oh,
Orthodoxy is one of the most important
things in my life. I I never take off my
stavro, never. I've been to Ayion Oros,
I've been to Jerusalem. I keep a picture
of Ayios Nektarios in my wallet right
here.
Yeah. So yeah, it's very very important
to me.
>> And were you visited when you were in
prison by
members of the Greek uh Not Not only did
a did a priest come regularly to give me
communion, Father Michael Calor, a
wonderful, kind gentleman,
but His Eminence Metropolitan Savvas
came Really? dressed in a as a bishop
with a hat and everything.
And then even even one of the guards
said to me You always laughing.
>> [laughter]
>> You always stop laughing.
Well, the guard said to me
"Who is that guy?" And I said, "He's the
archbishop."
>> [laughter]
>> Who is that guy? They They thought it
was Halloween for them.
>> They were very impressed.
>> Yeah. Like he had his staff and
everything. Yeah. He came
>> Yeah, he came prepared.
>> Yeah, yeah. He did that twice. He came
twice to visit me and gave me communion.
Uh-huh. So you got the Greek citizenship
before you went to prison.
>> Yes. And you were visited by Wow. Yes.
That's important.
So, ending. You've just spent the last
couple of days here with me in Cyprus
walking through the old town of Nicosia
inside the Venetian walls
showed you our Statue of Liberty
>> Yes. taking you to the green line that
separates us from our occupied lands
headed up to the Troodos Mountains
uh sharing souvla, bulguri, kleftiko
[laughter]
>> It was so good. and lamb liver. Yes, we
eat it and it's delicious and we love
it.
>> It's It's quite delicious, although it
requires lemon. It does.
And visiting the 1,000-year-old Saint um
John Lambadistis Monastery still
standing in remarkable condition and
protected as a UNESCO World Heritage
Site and met today
uh with Nicosia's mayor, Brountzos. With
a final day of activities planned for
tomorrow, how would you describe your
experiences here in Cyprus, your
second second homeland, those are
>> Yes. to our American viewers?
It's been wonderful here. I've only come
to Cyprus once before and it was 34
years ago. 30 Yeah, 4 years ago. I'm I'm
embarrassed that so many years have
passed. It's a completely different
country.
But I think I had forgotten
how powerful it is to see the green line
and the occupation
forces and settlers on the other side
with their very provocative actions. I
don't I don't I'm not trying to make the
situation between Cyprus and and the
Turkish occupiers worse than it is. But
it's
so much of it is done
just in order
to humiliate and to to rub it in where
they they have the one of the biggest
flags in the world on the side of the
mountain and it's lit up at night.
>> So we see it every day and
>> see it every day and every night.
You know? And we're reminded of the
occupation this way, 52 years. 52 years
of occupation. The call to prayer
pointed at the at the Greek
neighborhoods of the city.
You know, it's just it's very
frustrating. It's clear. It's clear to
me that
the Turks are not interested in in a
settlement. They like the status quo
just the way it is and that's not
acceptable.
Uh and your meeting today with the mayor
that I helped facilitate. Meet meeting
today with the mayor, very exciting.
Yeah, he showed you around. Yep. The
bird's-eye view.
>> He did. He took us up to the to the roof
of the municipality.
And as he said, it's only 70 m
from uh
from the gate leading into the Turkish
occupied sector of the city.
Uh it's it's very powerful. Very
powerful. And then, you know, you see on
the one side, you see
you see the Greek
part of the city. And it's modern and
it's first world and it has tall
buildings and an an economy that's
moving. And then you look at the Turkish
occupied side.
And it's
there's nothing happening there. It's
like out of the early '60s. There's
literally nothing happening there.
So, um did I get to ask you questions,
the personal questions, not these this
last one on Cyprus, that you didn't get
to be asked so far by other podcasters?
>> Yeah. Okay. So, well done.
>> That did you know John Sector will
resonate with the viewers and they get
to know more things about you. Even
though they think they know you, they
get to know more things about you. You
know, that's actually a funny thing and
you probably get that here in Cyprus,
too. But people some people
think that because they see you on
YouTube or Tik Tok or whatever that they
know you.
>> Mhm. And and that's fine. It's fun. I I
love to take selfies with people. I do
it every day, no matter where I am in
the world. I'm I always say yes. The
answer is always yes. But then there's
some people who fantasize a relationship
with you. Mhm.
And that becomes not fun. Okay. We don't
want that. No. Okay.
So, if the viewers have valued this
conversation, tap the bell, subscribe,
like and share, and help this channel,
this independent voice from the Eastern
Mediterranean, reach audiences in the
West. And John, thank you again. He left
his stall. Thank you. For coming here.
My pleasure.
>> spending these last few days with
family. you for everything. Your final
thoughts
for viewers?
Yeah, as I said in the last episode
this is the the biggest, the most
important
woman-run
political
commentary in the Eastern Mediterranean.
Geopolitical commentary. Geopolitical
commentary
in the Eastern Eastern Mediterranean and
Middle East. So, if you haven't
subscribed
liked, shared, do it now. We need more
commentary like this. Thank you, John.
Thank you. Thanks for being here.
>> [music]
[music]